(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-pro-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
#尾丸ポルカ生誕祭2026 新曲のお披露目あり！
#OmaruPolkaBirthday2026 New Song Reveal!
Glitter Love ポルカのライブ過去最多 ホロメンゲスト10名
Glitter Love - Most guests in Polka's live history (10 members)
1/30 21:00~
Jan 30, 21:00~
One, two, three, four
遥か空響いてる
Resounding in the distant sky,
祈りは奇跡に
prayers become miracles.
ETERNAL BLAZE
真夜中の蒼に溶けて
Melting into the midnight blue,
流れてく涙の粒
teardrops flow away.
迷いなく包み込む
Without hesitation, I met
温もりに出逢った
an embracing warmth.
真っ白な雪のように
Like pure white snow,
どこまでも素直なコトバ
words are honest everywhere.
鉄の羽根纏った
Clad in wings of iron,
僕を動かしてく
they move me forward.
傷つくたびに
Each time I get hurt,
優しくなれる
I become kinder.
君のその笑顔だけ
I only want to protect
守り抜きたい願いはひとつ
your smile, my one wish.
時空を越え刻まれた
Carved beyond time and space,
悲しみの記憶
memories of sadness.
まっすぐに受け止める
Accepting them directly,
君は光の女神
you are an angel of light.
あの日の胸に灯った
Lit in my heart that day,
永遠の炎
the eternal flame.
深い闇解き放って
Unleashing the deep darkness,
自由のトビラ開いてく
opening the door to freedom,
強く果てない未来へ
towards a strong, endless future.
冷たい緑の月に
In the cold green moon,
映し出すココロの夜
reflecting the shadow of my heart.
淋し気に呟いた
I whispered lonely,
君のそばにいたい
"I want to be by your side."
真実と向き合うこと
To face the truth,
教えてくれた勇気は
the courage you taught me
僕を駆け巡って
runs through me,
夢に目覚めていく
awakening me to the dream.
触れ合う気持ち
So our touching feelings
離れないように
won't separate,
しっかりと抱きしめて
holding on tightly,
確かな想い貫いてゆく
I'll carry through this certain feeling.
銀の海に隠した
Hidden in the silver sea,
空白のページ
a blank page.
君だけが知っている
Only you know the truth,
本当を僕に見せて
show it to me.
吹き荒れる切なさに
In the raging pain,
生まれゆく誓い
a vow is born.
もう何も怖くはないよ
I'm not afraid anymore,
結んだ視線逸らさずに
without averting our gaze.
大切な今始める Eternal Blaze
Starting this precious 'now', Eternal Blaze.
君が君でいられる場所
A place where you can be yourself,
幻に攫われぬように
so illusions won't snatch you away.
消えない雨の苦しみも
Even the pain of unending rain,
鍵を壊してぶつけてよ
break the lock and crash through.
隣にいるから
I'm by your side,
全てを信じて
so believe in everything.
時空を越え刻まれた
Carved beyond time and space,
悲しみの記憶
memories of sadness.
まっすぐに受け止める
Accepting them directly,
君は光の女神
you are an angel of light.
あの日の胸に灯った
Lit in my heart that day,
永遠の炎
the eternal flame.
解き放って
Unleash it,
自由の扉 開いてく
Opening the door to freedom.
強く果てない未来へ
Towards a strong, endless future.
そうきっとここから始まる
Yes, surely it starts from here.
お待たせみんなー！
Sorry to keep you waiting, everyone!
今年もポルカの誕生日が始まったー！
Polka's birthday has started again this year!
タイトルは、かっこいい『Glitter of Love』！
The title is the cool "Glitter of Love"!
というわけで、ハッシュタグはこちら！
So, the hashtag is this!
尾丸ポルカ生誕祭2026で
With #OmaruPolkaBirthday2026,
いっぱい、いーっぱいつぶやいてねー！
Please tweet lots and lots!
はーい！
Okaaay!
いやー、今回のテーマはまず、
Well, the theme this time is firstly,
愛と勇気と戦う女の子になってまーす！
I'm becoming a girl who fights with love and courage!
そして、見てくださいこのステージ！
And, please look at this stage!
えい！
Ei!
はーっ、すごい広い！
Haa, it's so wide!
おー、なんとですね、広いんですけれども
Oh, surprisingly, although it's wide,
まずスクリーンが超でっかい！大迫力！
First of all, the screen is super huge! Very impressive!
なんと何かいつもの3倍くらい頑張りました。
Surprisingly, somehow I worked about 3 times harder than usual.
いや頑張ってもらいました！
No, I had them work hard!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
というわけでですね、
So, with that said,
ここからゲストの方々がたくさんいらっしゃいます！
From here on, many guests will be joining!
もうホロメンだけなら多分
If we're talking about Holo-members only, probably
尾丸ポルカ史上最多のゲスト数だと思っております！
I think it's the highest number of guests in Omaru Polka history!
それをね、これからノンストップでお送りするので、
I'll be sending that to you non-stop from now on, so
楽しんでいってください！
Please enjoy it!
というわけで、行くぞー！
So, here we go!
遺伝子レベルの Independence
Gene-level Independence.
絶望も希望も抱いて
Embracing both despair and hope.
足掻け 命尽きるまで
Struggle until your life runs out.
光と飛沫の Kiss
A Kiss of light and spray.
恋のような虹の Birthday
A rainbow Birthday like love.
どんな美しき日も
No matter what beautiful day,
何か生まれ 何かが死ぬ
Something is born, something dies.
せめて歌を I love you
At least a song, I love you.
世界が酷い地獄だとしても
Even if the world is a cruel hell,
せめて伝えよう I love you
At least let me convey, I love you.
解放の時は来た
The time for liberation has come.
星降る天へと響き飛べ Everybody song
Resound and fly to the starry heavens, Everybody song.
Stardust
そして奇跡は待つものじゃなくて
And miracles aren't something you wait for,
その手で作るものと吠えろ
Roar that it's something you make with your own hands.
涙したがるオリガミを レクイエムにして
Making the origami that wants to cry into a requiem.
聖なる善の力で
With the power of holy goodness,
輝け Future world
Shine, Future world.
信じ照らせ 星天ギャラクシィクロス
Believe and illuminate, Seiten Galaxy Cross.
一人じゃないことを
That you are not alone.
やがて君は知る日のため
For the day you will eventually know.
指先伝う熱を
The heat transmitted through fingertips,
分かち合って明日に向かう
Sharing it and heading towards tomorrow.
永遠なる空に I feel you
In the eternal sky, I feel you.
自由の魂は殺せはしない
The soul of freedom cannot be killed.
不滅なる夢に I feel you
In the immortal dream, I feel you.
来世と手を握れ
Hold hands with the afterlife.
運命も終曲も断ち切る力で
With the power to sever fate and the finale.
そして重ねた夢...
And the layered dreams...
窮地となって闇を暴く
In a pinch, expose the darkness.
駆け抜けた背中には
On the backs of those who ran through,
神様も知らない
lies a history shining proudly,
歴史が光り誇る
that even God doesn't know.
My True Brave Heart
この絆 晴天ギャラクシィクロス
This bond is the Seiten Galaxy Cross.
逆光の翼で
With backlit wings,
Yes Just Dream
不死なる炎で
with undying flames,
Big Mission
過去も背負い戦おう
Let's fight, carrying our past as well.
そして奇跡は待つものじゃなくて
And miracles aren't something you wait for,
その手で作るものと吠えろ
roar that they are things you create with your own hands!
何度だって 何度だって
Again and again, again and again,
立ち上がろうか
shall we stand up?
生ある全の力で
With all the power of life,
輝け Future World
shine, Future World.
信じて照らせ
Believe and illuminate,
晴天ギャラクシィクロス
Seiten Galaxy Cross.
Try Try Trio Dreams
Let's Sing
Let's Swing
Let's Dance
Let's Bon
Let's Smile
Let's Fly
Uu~ Trigger
Let's Sing
Let's Swing
Let's Dance
Let's Bon
Let's Smile
Let's Fly
出会い頭で世界
The world at first encounter,
未来
the future.
1+1+1は
1+1+1 is
無限
infinite.
唇から零れる
Spilling from my lips,
歌は
the song is
La la lu li la la
プリズム眩しい光
A prism's dazzling light,
まっしぐら
heading straight for it.
三人寄ればバンバン最高
When three gather, it's the absolute best!
最強
The strongest!
始まるさ第一章
Chapter one is starting.
Love & Joy Together
ときめき止まらない
The excitement won't stop,
ハミング
Humming.
ちょっと億
A little bold,
感情ね
emotion right?
Call and Response
型破りでいいよね
It's okay to break the mold, right?
好きな
Favorite...
フレーズを
phrase!
シンコペーション 音符に
Syncopation, on the notes,
夢乗せて
riding on dreams,
君 あなたのもとへ
to you, to your side.
For You
もっともっと
More and more,
輝きあえるね
we can shine together.
みんな
Everyone!
Love Love
瞳スクリーンに
On the screen of your eyes,
いつだって
always,
笑顔 映し合おう
let's reflect each other's smiles.
Promise
君がいるからパワー生まれるよ
Because you are here, power is born.
今日も
Today too!
Try Try Trio Dreams
Let's Sing
Let's Swing
Let's Dance
Let's Bon
Let's Smile
Let's Fly
Uu~ Trigger
Let's Sing
Let's Swing
Let's Dance
Let's Bon
Let's Smile
Let's Fly
一緒だから感じる
Because we're together, I feel
Happy
Wanna Be
1×1×1は
1x1x1 is
無敵
invincible.
出し惜しみはなしで
Holding nothing back,
全部あげたい
I want to give you everything.
La la lu li la la
ハプニングさえも
Even mishaps are
Joyful
Wonderful
三人寄れば文殊もしのぐ
When three gather, we outshine Monju.
地味に
Simply,
魅せるよきっと
we'll surely charm you.
伝説のLive
A legendary Live
Uncontrollable
緩み糸
Loose threads,
解く法
a way to untie them.
ちゃんそん
Chanson
All the Welcome
カテゴライズいらないね
We don't need categories, do we?
好きだ
I love...
思い切り
with all my might!
四分音符の羽広げ
Spreading the wings of quarter notes,
ハトの奥の奥へ
deep into the depths of your heart.
For You
命は輝きで出来ているの
Life is made of brilliance.
Yes Yes
ビッグスクリーンも
Even on the big screen,
はみ出しちゃう
we're overflowing.
嬉しいや楽しい
Happiness and fun,
Pop Love
君を知って知らない自分に会えたよ
Knowing you, I met a version of myself I didn't know.
Try Try Trio Dreams
Let's Sing Let's Swing
Let's Dance
Let's Bon
Let's Smile
Let's Fly
君も一緒に
You too, together!
Let's Sing Let's Swing
Let's Dance
Let's Bon
Let's Smile
Let's Fly
型破りでいいよね
It's okay to break the mold, right?
好きな
Favorite...
フレーズを
phrase!
新音符に夢乗せて
Riding on dreams with new notes,
君 あなたのもとへ
to you, to your side.
For You
もっともっと
More and more,
輝きあえるね
we can shine together.
みんな
Everyone!
いつも笑顔写し合おう
Let's always mirror each other's smiles.
君がいるからパワー生まれるよ今日も
Because you are here, power is born again today.
Let's Go! Let's Peace! Let's Dance! Let's Boom!
Let's Smile! Let's Fly! Woo!
Let's Peace! Let's Swing! Let's Dance! Let's Boom!
Let's Smile! Let's Fly!
暗闇の真ん中
In the middle of the darkness,
真っ直ぐな眼差し
with a gaze looking straight ahead,
立ち上がる姿 ちゃんと見ていたよ
I was watching you stand up properly.
閉じ込められそうな
Seeming like it might be trapped,
心を奮い立たせ
I rouse my heart,
収まりきらない 輝きを放つ
releasing a radiance that cannot be contained.
満たされた胸の奥
Deep inside my fulfilled chest,
焼き付いたまま消せない
it's burned in and cannot be erased.
それだけでも自由になる 待っていて
Just that alone makes me free. Wait for me.
取り戻したい 光の世界
I want to take back the world of light.
その笑顔
That smile,
勇気
(Courage)
涙
tears,
夢希望の陽射し
(sunlight of dreams and hope)
君と明日を願う力で
With the power to wish for tomorrow with you,
生まれる私たちだけの Harmony
a Harmony belonging only to us is born.
響け
Resound!
それでも暗闇が
Even so, if darkness
訪れてしまうもの
were to visit us,
惑わされないで 君は君だから
don't be led astray; because you are you.
私が得た日々が
The days I gained
ハートを輝かせる
make my heart shine.
一人じゃないこと 気付かせてくれる
They make me realize I am not alone.
抱えきれないほどの
More than I can hold,
ありがとうの代わりに
instead of saying 'thank you',
鍵をかけて一つになる 受け止めて
I lock it up and we become one. Accept it.
取り戻すんだ 光の未来
We will take back the future of light.
今熱い
Now hot,
想い
(feelings)
繋ぐ
connecting,
声叶えに行くよ
(we go to grant the voice)
君と一緒に願える奇跡
The miracle of being able to wish together with you,
重ねて広がっていく Harmony
layering and expanding Harmony.
目覚める時が来たね
The time to awaken has come.
本当の自分になる
I become my true self.
満ちる運命
A fulfilling destiny.
取り戻したい 光の世界
I want to take back the world of light.
その笑顔
That smile,
勇気
(Courage)
涙
tears,
夢希望の陽射し
(sunlight of dreams and hope)
君と明日を願う力で
With the power to wish for tomorrow with you,
生まれる私たちだけの Harmony
a Harmony belonging only to us is born.
響け
Resound!
Day by day
日に日に募るの乙女心
A maiden's heart growing day by day.
クラス7、目の前の大人しい人
Class 7, the quiet person in front of me.
カッコよくはない　だけど優しい
He's not cool, but he is kind.
いつも頼れる彼
The guy I can always rely on.
放課後恋愛相談の帰り道
On the way home from discussing love after school.
なんだって話せる親友の女の子
The girl best friend I can talk to about anything.
スポーツ万能　勉強もできて
Good at sports, and good at studying too.
女子力マックスです
Her girl power is maxed out.
どこにでもある　よくあること
It's everywhere, a common thing.
急に彼女が
Suddenly she says...
あのね、実は私　好きな人がいるのって
"Hey, actually, I have someone I like."
ちょ、マジで！？
Wait, seriously!?
三角形　三角形の恋は気まぐれ
Triangle, triangular love is whimsical.
一瞬で　一瞬で崩れるバランス
In an instant, in an instant, the balance collapses.
ベタな漫画みたいなフラグ
A flag like in a cliché manga.
まさかね、自分も立てちゃうなんて残念すぎます
No way, it's too unfortunate that I'm raising one myself.
三角形　三角形の恋は不安定
Triangle, triangular love is unstable.
なんちゃって　なんちゃってじゃ済まないカテゴリ
A category that can't be dismissed with "just kidding".
恋と友情　ゆらゆらめいて
Love and friendship swaying.
なんか、青春しちゃいます
Like, I'm totally living my youth.
私、困っちゃいます
I'm in trouble.
完璧でお似合いすぎるわって　交運ない
They're perfect and match too well, I have no luck.
悔しいけど　とかそんなんじゃなくて本心
"It's frustrating," but it's not like that, it's my true feeling.
ていうか既に　応援モード
Or rather, I'm already in cheering mode.
むしろ清々しい
Actually, it feels refreshing.
だけど彼女は　不思議な顔
But she has a strange look on her face.
真剣な目で
With serious eyes...
そうじゃなくて私、あなたが好き、ごめんって
"That's not it, I like YOU, sorry."
ちょ、マジで！？
Wait, seriously!?
三角形　三角形の恋は気まぐれ
Triangle, triangular love is whimsical.
一瞬で　一瞬で崩れるバランス
In an instant, in an instant, the balance collapses.
私、あなた、彼女と私
Me, you, her and me.
超絶複雑百合展開は想定外です
A super complex yuri development is unexpected.
三角形　三角形の恋は不安定
Triangle, triangular love is unstable.
なんちゃって　なんちゃってじゃ済まないカテゴリ
A category that can't be dismissed with "just kidding".
解けないパズル　与えたもうた神よ
God who gave us an unsolvable puzzle.
うなんじゃいます
I'm groaning.
私、悩んじゃいます
I'm worried.
あーもう！すごいヤバイ！
Ah jeez! It's super crazy!
来たよ！来たけど、ってそういう意味じゃなくて
It came! It came but, not in that meaning...
だって女の子同士だし
But we are both girls.
ねぇ神様　どうしたらいいの？
Hey God, what should I do?
私どうしたいの？
What do I want to do?
HELP ME!
なんか変だ　愛に国境も歳も性別も関係ない
Something's weird. Love has no borders, age, or gender.
けど、けど、けど
But, but, but!
三角形　三角形の恋は気まぐれ
Triangle, triangular love is whimsical.
一瞬で　一瞬で崩れるバランス
In an instant, in an instant, the balance collapses.
普通の恋　夢見てたのに
Even though I dreamed of a normal love.
ノーマル設定の私じゃちょっと無理ゲーすぎます
For me with normal settings, this is a bit too much of an impossible game.
三角形　三角形の恋は不安定
Triangle, triangular love is unstable.
なんちゃって　なんちゃってじゃ済まないカテゴリ
A category that can't be dismissed with "just kidding".
彼女のこと　好きになれたらなんて
If only I could fall in love with her...
妄想しちゃいます
I'm starting to have delusions.
私、どうかしてます
I'm going crazy.
交互と続く衝動 衝動
Alternating, continuous impulses.
喪失は絶対零度って
Loss is absolute zero.
今夜は臨界でしょう 悲しみが
Tonight, the sadness reaches critical mass.
混沌の子守唄 歌ってるよ
Singing a lullaby of chaos.
運命に理由があるのならば
If there is a reason for this fate,
全てを賭けてみたいの
I want to bet everything on it.
あなたを守りたい
I want to protect you.
どこまでも高く飛べるわ
I can fly higher than anywhere.
どこまでも強く強くなれるわ
I can become stronger, stronger than anything.
信じて私に出会えた奇跡
Believe in the miracle of our meeting.
火に拓くは不死鳥の炎抱いて
Opening in the fire, embracing the phoenix's flame.
あなたのドグマ
Your dogma.
Black out Black out
眼差し 泣きたくなるの
Your gaze makes me want to cry.
Flashback Flashback
振り解け onset
Shake off the onset.
挑み続けろ
Keep challenging.
飄々と佇むホットスポット
Standing aloof in the hot spot.
私が必要でしょ
You need me, right?
今夜は臨界でしょう 正しさが
Tonight, righteousness reaches critical mass.
それらしい最前線に押し出すよ
Pushing out to the plausible front lines.
運命に理由があるのならば
If there is a reason for this fate,
優しい世界をあげたい
I want to give you a gentle world.
あなたを包むわ
I will wrap around you.
どこまでも速く射抜くわ
I will shoot through faster than anything.
どこまでも熱く熱く焦がすわ
I will burn hotter, hotter than anything.
信じて私に出会えた奇跡
Believe in the miracle of our meeting.
火に拓くは不死鳥の炎抱いて
Opening in the fire, embracing the phoenix's flame.
あなたのドグマ
Your dogma.
Black out Black out
肩越し 光を見せて
Show me the light over your shoulder.
Flashback Flashback
許さない Regret
I won't forgive regret.
進み続けろ
Keep moving forward.
尽きるまで
Until it runs out.
そばにいると
When I'm by your side.
鼓動が早くて 目眩がする
My heartbeat is fast, I feel dizzy.
全て捧げる
I'll dedicate everything.
もう決めたの
I've already decided.
最期のチャンスだから
Because this is the last chance.
もう離さない
I won't let go anymore.
あなたに燃ゆる
Burning for you.
未来の風
Wind of the future.
舞い上がって行け
Soar up high.
どこまでも高く飛べるわ
I can fly higher than anywhere.
どこまでも強く強くなれるわ
I can become stronger, stronger than anything.
信じて私に出会えた奇跡
Believe in the miracle of our meeting.
闇夜も望めば 白夜にするから
If you wish for it, I'll turn even the dark night into a midnight sun.
火に拓くは不死鳥の炎抱いて
Opening in the fire, embracing the phoenix's flame.
あなたのドグマ
Your dogma.
Black out Black out
眼差し 泣きたくなるの
Your gaze makes me want to cry.
Flashback Flashback
振り解け onset
Shake off the onset.
挑み続けろ
Keep challenging.
Black out Black out
肩越し 光を見せて
Show me the light over your shoulder.
Flashback Flashback
許さない Regret
I won't forgive regret.
進み続けろ
Keep moving forward.
ダイアモンド クレバス
作詞: hal 作曲: 菅野よう子
Diamond Crevasse
Lyrics: hal / Composition: Yoko Kanno
Wow wo...
神様に恋をしてた頃は
When I was in love with God,
こんな別れが来るとは思ってなかったよ
I never thought a parting like this would come.
Uh...
もう二度と触れられないなら
If I can never touch you again,
せめて最後に
At least, for the last time,
もう一度抱きしめて欲しかったよ
I wanted you to hold me once more.
Uh... It's long long goodbye
さよなら　さよなら
Goodbye, goodbye,
何度だって
No matter how many times,
自分に　無上に
Telling myself heartlessly,
言い聞かせて
Over and over again.
手を振るのは優しさだよね
Waving goodbye is an act of kindness, isn't it?
今強さが欲しい
I want strength right now.
あなたに出会い STAR 輝いて
Meeting you, the STAR shone,
アタシが生まれて
And I was born.
愛すればこそ
Because I love,
愛あればこそ
Because there is love.
希望のない　奇跡を待って
Waiting for a hopeless miracle,
どうなるの
What will happen?
涙に滲む
Blurred by tears,
惑星の瞬きは gone
The twinkling of the stars is gone.
Uh...
忘れないよ
I won't forget,
アナタの温もりも
Your warmth,
その優しさも
That kindness,
全て包んでくれた両手も
And the two hands that wrapped around everything.
Uh... It's long long goodbye
さよなら　さよなら
Goodbye, goodbye,
愛しい人
My beloved.
アナタがいたから
Because you were there,
歩いてこれた
I could walk this far.
ひとりなんかじゃなかったよね
I wasn't alone, was I?
今答えが欲しい
I want an answer right now.
燃えるような流星　捕まえて
Catch a burning meteor,
火を灯して
And light a fire.
愛していたい
I want to keep loving,
愛されてたい
I want to be loved.
冷え切ったカラダひとつで
With just one frozen body,
世界はどうなるの
What will become of the world?
張り続けてた　虚勢が溶けてく
The bravado I kept up is melting away,
long for...
どうしてなろう
Why is it?
涙溢れて
Tears overflowing,
止められない
I can't stop them.
Uh...
Ah...
あなたに出会い STAR 輝いて
Meeting you, the STAR shone,
アタシが生まれて
And I was born.
愛すればこそ
Because I love,
愛あればこそ
Because there is love.
希望のない　奇跡を待って
Waiting for a hopeless miracle,
どうなるの
What will happen?
涙に滲む
Blurred by tears,
惑星の瞬きは gone
The twinkling of the stars is gone.
もし生まれ変わって
If we are reborn,
また巡り会えるなら
And meet again,
その時もきっと
At that time, surely,
アタシを見つけ出して
Find me again.
もう二度と離さないで
Don't ever let me go again,
捕まえてて
Hold on to me.
…じゃないと
...that it's not...
ささやいてほしい
I want you to whisper
二人
to the two of us.
Paradise Lost
聖なる瞳が
If your holy eyes
痛みを映したら
reflect the pain,
振り向いてごらん
turn around and look,
情熱放つTrick
a trick that releases passion.
崩れる足元
With our footing crumbling,
二人は戻れない
the two of us cannot return.
差し伸べた手を
Don't let go of
解かないで
the hand reaching out.
消えるよまた
They are disappearing again,
優しい日々が
the gentle days.
思い出を汚すのは
I won't forgive
許せない
defiling the memories.
ここは裏切りの楽園
Here is the paradise of betrayal.
さまよう心の果てに
At the end of a wandering heart,
光を求めて
seeking the light.
祈る言葉届けあなたに
May the words of prayer reach you.
囚われの羽が
The captured wings
遥かな空へと向かう
head towards the distant sky.
信じたいよ私たち
I want to believe that we
孤独じゃない
are not alone.
分かり合う
Understanding each other...
(求め合う)
(Seeking each other...)
絆の中
within this bond.
離さないで
Don't let go...
(離れない)
(I won't leave...)
始まるDestiny
Destiny begins.
Lost the Paradise Ah...
消えるよまた
They are disappearing again,
優しい日々が
the gentle days.
思い出を汚すのは
I won't forgive
許せない
defiling the memories.
ここは裏切りの楽園
Here is the paradise of betrayal.
さまよう心の果てに
At the end of a wandering heart,
光を求めて
seeking the light.
祈る言葉届けあなたに
May the words of prayer reach you.
囚われの羽が
The captured wings
遥かな空へと向かう
head towards the distant sky.
信じたいよ私たち
I want to believe that we
孤独じゃない
are not alone.
分かり合う
Understanding each other...
(求め合う)
(Seeking each other...)
絆の中
within this bond.
見つめて Paradise Lost
Gazing at Paradise Lost
Wow wow wow...
やっとみんな会えたね！
Finally met everyone!
Nonstop! Nonstop! The finish!
高鳴った全力走りたい
My heart is pounding, I want to run with all my might
芝と砂と君の
Turf, sand, and your...
追い切りメニュー
...training menu
多難
Many difficulties
越えば絶景
Overcome them for a superb view
Wow wow...
揃って
Together
FIGHT! FIGHT! FIGHT!
重なった全力上がりたい
Overlapping full power, I want to rise
譲れない夢の途中
In the middle of an unyielding dream
走れよ
Run!
此処から最高ストーリー
The best story starts from here
Oh oh oh...
あぁ 焦がれる方へ
Ah, towards where I yearn
語り合ったメモリー
Memories we talked about together
もう ドキドキも ときめきも
Already, the pounding heart and the excitement
抑えられない止まんない
Can't suppress it, won't stop
熱いハラハラが止まらない
The hot suspense won't stop
君と
With you
走り競いゴール目指し
Running, competing, aiming for the goal
遥か響け届け MUSIC
Echo far away, reach, MUSIC
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い
Always, always, always, always, these feelings
夢がきっと叶うなら
If the dream will surely come true
あの日君に感じた
That day I felt within you
何かを信じて
Believing in something
春も夏も秋も冬も
Spring, summer, autumn, and winter too
越え願い焦がれ走れ
Overcome, wish, yearn, run
勝利へ
To victory
Nonstop! Nonstop! The finish!
高鳴った全力弾けたい
Pounding heart, I want to burst open with full power
大出会い決意
A great encounter, determination
絆になった
Became a bond
感謝
Gratitude
本気で叫べ
Scream seriously
Wow wow...
揃って
Together
FIGHT! FIGHT! FIGHT!
重なった全力笑いたい
Overlapping full power, I want to laugh
タフのど真ん中
Right in the middle of the turf
リアルに
For real,
此処から上昇ストーリー
a rising story starts from here
Oh oh oh...
あぁ 駆け抜けた日々
Ah, the days we ran through
語り合ったグローリー
The glory we talked about together
今 答えたい 生きてると
Now I want to answer that I am alive
背中押す声熱くなる
The voices pushing my back are getting hot
夢は夢のまま終われない
Dreams cannot end as just dreams
君と
With you
未来描きゴール目指し
Drawing the future, aiming for the goal
狙え挑め掴め WINNING
Aim, challenge, grab, WINNING
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い
Always, always, always, always, these feelings
夢はきっと叶うから
Because dreams will surely come true
あの日君が流した
That day you shed...
涙も信じて
...believe in those tears too
雨も風も雲も闇も
Rain, wind, clouds, and darkness too
越え願い焦がれ走れ
Overcome, wish, yearn, run
勝利へ
To victory
揺るぎない覚悟決して
Determining unwavering resolve
一つ二つ共に綴る記録
Records spelled out one by one together
背中に迫る迷い振り払え
Shake off the hesitation closing in on my back
今の自分追い越すだけ
Just overtaking my current self
勝ちたい
I want to win
君と勝ちたい！
I want to win with you!
君と
With you
走り競いゴール目指し
Running, competing, aiming for the goal
遥か響け届け MUSIC
Echo far away, reach, MUSIC
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い
Always, always, always, always, these feelings
夢がきっと叶うなら
If the dream will surely come true
It's finally the true end
I'm ready for... my destiny
I'm ready for... STARTING OVER
やっと幕を下ろせた
I've finally brought the curtain down,
最後の瞬間まで
until the very last moment.
わたしは精一杯に
With all my might,
わたしをやりきった
I played my part to the fullest.
終演の続きは
What comes after the finale,
誰も知らなくていい
no one needs to know.
涙を置いて
Leaving my tears behind,
新しい旅に出よう
let's set out on a new journey.
熱狂はあなたを選ぶ
The frenzy chooses you;
違う結末だっただけ
it was just a different ending.
同じ愛になれなかった
We couldn't become the same love,
Destiny
これまでの全てを
It was a love where I felt like
差し出すような愛だった
I was offering up everything until now.
世界の意味が変わるくらいに
Enough to change the meaning of the world,
肯定された気がしたんだ
I felt like I was truly affirmed.
何気なさの中で
Within the casual moments,
気づけた最初の奇跡が
the first miracle I noticed was...
あなたでよかった
I'm glad it was you.
わたしでよかった
I'm glad it was me.
心から思えたよ
I could think that from the bottom of my heart.
ずっと遠い未来も
Even in the far distant future,
ちゃんと覚えていよう
I'll remember it properly.
自分の抱きしめ方
How to embrace myself,
明日の願いかた
and how to wish for tomorrow.
あなたがいなくても
Even if you aren't here,
わたしの片隅で
in a corner of my heart,
優しい光
a gentle light,
消えたりしないとわかる
I know it won't ever vanish.
今はまだ手を振れるほど
Now, while we are still close enough to wave,
道は別れたばかりで
our paths have just parted.
後ろ髪に風を感じながら
Feeling the wind on the back of my hair,
それまでの全てが
Everything up until then
あなたに出会うためだった
was so that I could meet you.
どの瞬間もムダじゃないこと
That no moment was a waste,
本当の意味で知れたから
I've learned what that truly means.
次の曲がり角も
Even at the next turning point,
自分らしさで選べるはず
I should be able to choose my own way.
いつかに繋がる
Connecting to someday,
新しい一歩
a new step.
信じて歩き出そう
Let's believe and start walking.
心から誰かを愛せた
I was able to love someone from my heart.
あの日々は
Those days were,
間違いなくわたしの Destiny Ah,
without a doubt, my Destiny. Ah,
これまでの全てが
Everything up to now
新しい力をくれる
gives me new power.
どの瞬間もムダじゃないなら
If no moment was a waste,
何が起きても大丈夫
then whatever happens, I'll be okay.
だから
So...
次の物語も
Even in the next story,
自分らしさで選べるはず
I should be able to choose my own way.
いつかに繋がる
Connecting to someday,
わたしのはじまり
my beginning.
信じて歩き出そう
Let's believe and start walking.
いつかに繋がる　わたしのはじまり　信じて歩き出そう
It will connect someday. My beginning. Let's believe and walk forward.
再び幕は上がる
The curtain rises again.
聴いていただいたのは新曲の『Starting Over』でした！
What you just heard was my new song, 'Starting Over'!
はい、新年一発目、新曲の初披露ということで、ぬるっとね、新曲をやってしまったんですが。
Yes, as the first one of the new year, a new song reveal, I just kind of slipped it in there smoothly.
平成感のある、懐かしみの感じの楽曲を、こちらですね、歌わせていただいたんですけれども。
I had the pleasure of singing this song which has a bit of a Heisei-era, nostalgic feel to it.
この後、この曲が、えーと24時から...
After this, this song will be... at 24:00...
あと猛数時間後か、24時からですね。
Just a few hours from now, at 24:00.
1月30日の24時から配信リリースされます！たくさん聴いてください！
It will be released on streaming from 24:00 on Jan 30th! Please listen to it a lot!
今年もね、たくさんオリ曲出していきたいです！
I want to release lots of original songs this year too!
そしてそして、もうMCがね、実は最後なのでね、
And also, actually, this is the last MC part,
えーとこの配信の後にはメンバー限定の配信もあるのでよろしくお願いします。
so there will be a members-only stream after this one, so please check that out.
よしよしよし！グッズ紹介！
Alright, alright, alright! Goods introduction!
え、ここには同期のねぽらぼ大集合ということで、えーと...
Eh, since the gen-mate NePoLaBo have gathered here in full force...
ね... ぽ... ら... ぼ... 集まれ！
Ne... Po... La... Bo... Assemble!
イェーーーイ！
Yeeeaaah!
チャチャチャチャ。初めて呼びました。どうも。
Cha-cha-cha-cha. I invited you for the first time. Hello.
初だっけ？
Was it the first time?
ポルカチャンネル初です。
First time on Polka Channel.
ポルカチャンネルお邪魔します。やあやあ。
Thanks for having us on Polka Channel. Hi hi.
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがと！
Thanks!
ここまでが流れでございます。
And that concludes the scripted flow.
ずっと待ってたから。
We've been waiting forever.
グッズをね、紹介させていただきたいと思います。皆さんね、失礼ながらあのリアクションなどを各々取っていただいて。
I'd like to introduce the goods. If you could all please provide your reactions.
ガヤスタ？
Gaya-style?
ガヤだガヤだ！
It's gaya time! Noise squad!
というわけで、尾丸ポルカ誕生日記念グッズ2026！ラインナップはこちら！
So, here is the lineup for Omaru Polka Birthday Commemorative Goods 2026!
ドン！
Bam!
というわけで、素晴らしい今回もラインナップが揃っております。
As you can see, we have a wonderful lineup gathered this time as well.
え、すごいけど... あれ？なんかちょっとあれが...
Eh, it's amazing but... Huh? Something is a bit...
あれ？あれ？あれ？
Huh? Huh? Huh?
盛ってます？盛ってない？
Are you padding? Or not?
盛ってませんよ！盛ってません！
I'm not padding! I am not!
というわけで、まず一つ一つフォーカスしていきましょう。
Anyway, let's focus on them one by one.
まずはこちら！
First up is this!
ポルカのね、初めての抱き枕カバーになっております。
It's Polka's first ever Dakimakura (Body Pillow) Cover.
すごい！可愛い！
Wow! Cute!
パンツ履いてません？丸出しじゃないですか？
Is she not wearing panties? Isn't it totally exposed?
部屋着だよ！部屋着！
It's loungewear! Loungewear!
表が通常衣装で、裏は彼シャツになってます。
The front is the standard outfit, and the back is the 'Boyfriend Shirt' style.
彼シャツ！！
Boyfriend Shirt!!
着ていただきました。
We had her wear it.
続きまして、ドン！
Moving on, Bam!
歴代衣装のポルカランダムラバーストラップです！
Polka's Random Rubber Straps featuring past costumes!
これまでの衣装のラバーストラップ、こちらノイニミ先生に描いていただきました！
Rubber straps of my costumes so far, drawn by Noinimi-sensei!
え、めっちゃいいじゃんこれ。
Eh, this is actually really good.
続きましてこちら！
Next up is this!
どれもこれも宝物・思い出バインダー！
Treasure Every Memory Binder!
最近みんなも特典でチェキ風のブロマイドカード出したりしてるから...
Lately everyone's been releasing Instax-style bromide cards as bonuses...
そして続きましてはこちら！
And next up is this!
ポルカのしっぽキーホルダー！
Polka's Tail Keychain!
平成レトロみたいな感じ。
It has a Heisei-retro vibe.
そしてボイスはこちら！
And the voice pack is this!
ASMRボイスです。
It's an ASMR voice.
『彼シャツポルカの...』というね、ちょっと何かタイトルも...
Titled 'Boyfriend Shirt Polka's...' which is a bit...
狙ってるじゃん。エッチコンロ点火。
You're doing it on purpose. Lewd Stove Ignition.
やめてよ！
Stop it!
なんで今日同期呼んじゃったんだろうって一瞬思った今。恥ずかしくなっちゃった。
I just wondered for a second why I invited my gen-mates today. I got embarrassed.
(点火音) カチッ。ボウ！シュウ...
(Ignition sounds) Click. Whoosh! Shhh...
フルセット購入特典になっております。こちら！
This is the Full Set Purchase Bonus. Here!
チェキ風ブロマイドカード、数量限定が直筆メッセージ、
Instax-style bromide card. The limited quantity version has a handwritten message,
箔押し複製サインになっております。
and foil-stamped duplicated autograph.
なんかちょっと そういったボイスになって こっちもASMRになってます
It's become a bit of a whispering voice, so this side has also become ASMR.
恥ずかしいな！みんなとやるのこれ
This is embarrassing! Doing this with everyone.
なんかエッチな女になっちまって
Somehow, I've ended up like a lewd woman.
いいじゃない
Isn't it fine?
すみません 新年もね えっと皆さん改めてこれからよろしくお願いします
Sorry. For the New Year too, um, everyone, once again, please treat me well from now on.
お願いします！
Please!
というわけでね 今日はみんなで最後一緒に歌うために呼んできたということで 準備してきます！
So, today I called everyone to sing together at the end, so we'll go get ready!
行ってきます！
We're off!
じゃあこっちだ！
Then, this way!
右だね
Right side, huh.
バイバーイ！
Bye bye!
脚本は捨てちゃおうか
Shall we throw away the script?
サシカット焼き付けよう
Let's burn in the sash-cut.
アドリブの熱いパフォーマンス
A hot ad-lib performance.
屋根裏を飛び出して
Jumping out of the attic,
壮大なステージに響く
Resounding on the magnificent stage,
特別なストーリー
A special story.
瞼の裏には
Behind the eyelids,
虹が紡ぐ
A rainbow weaves,
星空のメモリー
A memory of the starry sky.
等身大の愛を込めて
Putting in life-sized love,
想像を超える世界へ
To a world beyond imagination.
誰も知らない
No one knows,
でしょ？
Right?
Are you ready?
どんな未来が見に来ようなんて
Whatever future comes to visit,
自由だ笑っちゃうよね
It's freedom, it makes you laugh, right?
ホログラムよりも先へ
Further than the hologram,
誰だって置いてかないよご覧
Look, I won't leave anyone behind.
感性が呼んでいる
Sensibility is calling.
ステップからバッと照らす
Suddenly illuminating from the step,
人生のスポットライト
The spotlight of life.
薔薇色のプレミアショー
A rose-colored premiere show.
ここが特等席よ
Here is the special seat.
ポジは素日和
Positives are in plain weather,
天気次第のエチュード
An etude depending on the weather.
まるで獲物語
Like a prey's story,
捕まえてよ
Catch me.
待って
Wait,
ほら
Look,
待って
Wait.
予想もできない展開に
In an unpredictable development,
ステージは揺れる
The stage shakes.
特別なストーリー
A special story.
耳を澄ましたら
If you listen closely,
月と雨粒のハーモニー
The harmony of the moon and raindrops.
浮かぶふわふわの空想
Floating fluffy fantasies,
暴走？底なしの本能
Rampage? Bottomless instinct.
すべて知りたいでしょ
You want to know everything, right?
Hey guys！叫べ 気分は最高？
Hey guys! Shout! Is the feeling the best?
最高！
The best!
Come on！もっと叫べ 気分は最高？
Come on! Shout more! Is the feeling the best?
最高！
The best!
ポルカ終わるか？
Will Polka end?
終わらない It's showtime！
It won't end! It's showtime!
繋いだ手離さないでなんてね
Don't let go of my hand, or something like that.
どうしたって重たくなっちゃって困るわ
No matter what, it gets heavy and it's troubling.
いつの日かエピローグを一緒に綴ろう
Let's spell out the epilogue together someday.
きっと約束よ
It's definitely a promise.
Life goes on！
Life goes on!
どんな未来が見に来よう
Whatever future comes to visit,
なんて自由だ笑っちゃうよね
It's such freedom, it makes you laugh, right?
ホログラムよりも先へ
Further than the hologram,
夢のような花舞台に
On the flower stage like a dream,
感情を馳せたら
If you let your feelings run,
ステップからバッと照らす
Suddenly illuminating from the step,
人生のスポットライト
The spotlight of life.
薔薇色のプレミアショー
A rose-colored premiere show.
どこへだって添い遂げたい
I want to be together anywhere.
ここが特等席よ
Here is the special seat.
あんたにゃ
For you...
もったいない
...it's a waste.
アタシャホント
I'm truly a...
ナイスバディ
...nice body.
自分で
To say it...
いう位
...myself.
タダじゃない
It's not for free...
じゃない
...is it?
熱けりゃ
If it's hot...
冷ませばいい
...just cool it down.
寂しけりゃ EVERYBODY
If you're lonely, everybody...
誰にも
To anyone...
わからない
...unknown.
恋愛って
Love is...
いつ火がつくのか
...when does the fire ignite?
DYNAMITE
恋はDYNAMITE
Love is dynamite.
どんなに
No matter how...
不景気だって
...bad the economy is...
恋はインフレーション
Love is inflation.
こんなに
This much...
優しくされちゃ
...kindness shown to me...
みだら
...is indecent.
明るい
A bright...
未来に
...future...
就職希望だわ
...I hope to get a job in.
Wow wow wow wow
日本の未来は
Japan's future is...
Wow wow wow wow
世界がうらやむ
...what the world envies.
Yeah yeah yeah yeah
恋をしようじゃないか
Let's fall in love, shall we?
Wow wow wow wow
Dance! Dancin' all of the night
なんだか
Somehow...
物足りない
...it's not enough.
どこにいたって
Wherever I am...
愛しててほしいわ
...I want you to keep loving me.
自分で
Conveying it...
伝えるの
...myself...
恥ずかしい
...is embarrassing...
じゃない
...isn't it?
理想の
If we are an ideal...
二人なら
...couple...
憧れよ EVERYBODY
...we are admired, everybody.
誰しも
Everyone...
気付いてない
...hasn't realized.
恋愛って
Love is...
夢の落とし穴
...a trap of dreams.
Mystery
恋はMystery
Love is a mystery.
どんなに
No matter how...
不自然だって
...unnatural it is...
恋のインサイダー
...love's insider.
それでも
Even so...
上手にされちゃ
...if done skillfully...
ハラハラ
...it's suspenseful.
幸せ
Happy...
来る日も
...days will come...
キャンセル待ちなんです
...I'm waiting for a cancellation.
Wow wow wow wow
あんたの笑顔は
Your smile is...
Wow wow wow wow
世界がうらやむ
...what the world envies.
Yeah yeah yeah yeah
夢があるじゃないか
There is a dream, isn't there?
Wow wow wow wow
Dance! Dancin' all of the night
フワフワフワフワ
Fuwa fuwa fuwa fuwa!
Love love love machine
Love love love station
Love love love factory
Love! Love is so wonderful
Yeah!
日本の未来は
Japan's future is...
Wow wow wow wow
世界がうらやむ
...what the world envies.
Yeah yeah yeah yeah
恋をしようじゃないか
Let's fall in love, shall we?
Wow wow wow wow
Dance! Dancin' all of the night
あんたもあたしも
You and I too...
Wow wow wow wow
みんなも社長さんも
...everyone and the boss too!
Yeah yeah yeah yeah
Dance! Dancin' all of the night
Love machine
#尾丸ポルカ生誕祭2026 1/30 21:00~
#OmaruPolkaBirthday2026 Jan 30, 21:00~
新曲のお披露目あり！ Glitter of Love
New song reveal! "Glitter of Love"
ポルカのライブ過去最多 ホロメンゲスト10名
Most guests in Polka's live history: 10 Holomembers